# DAMPELLA GAMAGE **AVISHKA KAVINDA**

+94 76 884 9669

avishkakavinda@proton.me

Gonapinuwala, Galle, Sri Lanka

www.linkedin.com/in/acekavi

www.github.com/acekavi

## **PROFILE INFO**

As a computer science major at the University of Westminster, UK, I am a quick learner and creative thinker with a passion for software development. With over five years of experience as a graphic design freelancer, I have honed my skills in creative problemsolving, attention to detail, and communication. During my recent six-month internship at Infor Nexus as a software engineering intern, I further developed my technical skills in Java and Spring Boot, as well as Angular and Ionic for web and mobile application development. I am eager to continue growing as a developer and contributing my skills to a dynamic team of professionals.

Languages:

English -

## **EDUCATION HISTORY**

### **BSc Honors in Computer Science**

2020 - Present Informatics Institute of Technology in Affiliation with University of Westminster, London

## **GCE Advanced Level Physical Science Stream**

2018 Richmond College Galle

#### **GCE Ordinary Level**

2015

Richmond College Galle

## **Complete Python** Developer in 2022: Zero to **Mastery**

2022 - 2023 **UDEMY** 

# SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- UI/UX Design
- Frontend Development
- Backend Development
- Illustration
- · Graphic Design

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Graphic Designer**

Fiverr Freelancing | 2017 - 2022

• Develop graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos, and Internet websites.

Bē www.behance.net/acekavi

#### **Software Engineering Intern**

Infor Nexus | 2022 - 2023

- · Worked with Java and Spring Boot, which are used extensively in the core of the organization.
- · Worked on the Quality Assurance application, which involved developing web and mobile applications using Angular and Ionic.
- Developed a strong understanding of REST APIs and non-relational databases while working on the core application.
- · Contributed to the development of the audit page and PDF export feature for the mobile application in the Quality Assurance application.
- Improved my communication and collaboration skills by working closely with local and international team members.

# HOBBYS & INTERESTS

- Illustrations
- UI Designing
- Competitive Gaming (FPS)
- · Working out
- Travelling

## TECHNICAL SKILLS























# PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Music Player using ReactJS
  - http://acekavi.github.io/musicplayer
- Personal Portfolio Site
  - https://www.acekavi.me

## SOFT SKILLS

- Strong Communication Skills
- Team Player
- · Positive attitude
- · Self-improving
- Creative Thinking

# **RFFFRFNCFS**

#### Mr. Pumudu Fernando

Senior Lecturer at IIT | Project Mentor pumudu.f@iit.ac.lk +94 76 820 9742

#### Mr. Dilan Shaminda

Senior Lecturer at IIT | 3DIM Mentor dilan.s@iit.ac.lk +94 76 820 9891

## ACADEMIC PERFORMANCE

- Software Development I | Python | 91
  - Math game that store high scores in a SQL database and a .csv file
  - Application to track student progress and grades
- Computer System Fundamentals | 89
- Software Development II | Java | 83
  - Hotel room booking system
- Web Design and Development | HTML, CSS, JS | 72
  - http://acekavi.github.io/siteLanka/quiz
  - http://acekavi.github.io/siteLanka/aboutUs
  - http://acekavi.github.io/siteLanka/Resume/avishka
- Advanced client side development | Jquery, Bootstrap, ES6 |
  - E-commerce website for Clarks Shoes
  - http://acekavi.me/clarkslk
- Object Oriented Programming | Java, Java Swing | 71
  - Formula 1 Championship manager
- Database Systems | ERDs, SQL, XML | 87
- 3D Interactive media | Unity, C# for Unity | 77
  - Restaurant Simulator in a Lego Environment
- Software Development Group Project | 68
  - A mobile application to detect snakes species in Sri Lanka through a real-time video footage
  - Yolov4 Object detection model is used in an android mobile application using tensor flow lite

# EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- FOSS Community of IIT | 2019 2022
- Mozilla Club of IIT | 2019 2022
- Richmond College IT Society | Vice President | 2017
- Richmond Live Team | 2018 -2020
- Infor Social Media Team | 2022 2023
- CodeSprint 2022 | Participation
- HackX 2021 | Participation